Henry DeWolf Smyth Papers 1885-1987 Mss.Ms.Coll.15
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Professional Correspondence, 1916-86
  - Stephens, William E., 1966
  - Stepp, Howard W.
  - Sterling, J. E. Wallace, 1964
  - Stern, Philip M., 1967-68
    JRO case
  - Stevens, D. L., 1956
  - Stevens, George, 1951-56
  - Stevens, Richard K., 1955
  - Stevens, Sydney G., 1967
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1956
  - Stevenson, J. H., n.d.
    memos on LASL
  - Stevenson, John D.
  - Stevenson, R. S., 1960-61
    model C stellarator
  - Stevenson, Stuart R., 1946
  - Stever, H. Guyford
  - Stewart, George W., 1945-54
  - Stewart, Irvin
    - Apgar, F. R.
    - Lawrence, Ernest O.
    - Vanden Bulck, C.
    NDRC/OSRD contracts w/Princeton
    - Folder #1, 1940-41
    - Folder #2, 1941-42
    - Folder #3, 1942
    - Folder #4, 1942-43
    - Folder #5, 1943-45; n.d.
  - Stewart, James H., 1977
  - Stewart, John Q., 1949-55
    nuclear explosions & weather
  - Stewart, R. B.
  - Stewart, Ward, 1947
  - Stibravy, William J.
    - see Sisco, Joseph J.
  - Stillwell, H. S.
    - see Fletcher, C. H.
  - Stirton, W. E., 1957
  - Stix, Thomas, 1959
  - Stohlman, W. F., 1945
  - Stone, J. L., 1955
  - Stone, R. S.
    - see Ser. II, Mulliken Comm.
  - Stone, Shepard, 1966
  - Storer, Bonnie, 1958
  - Stowell, Averill
  - Strager, Luther M.
  - Strain, Charles V.
  - Stranger, E. L.
    - see Ser. IV, Department of State. U.S. position on the future role of...
  - Stratton, F. J. M., 1921; 1952
  - Stratton, Henry M.
    - see Kusaka, Shuichi
  - Stratton, L. D., 1950
  - Strauser, Wilbur A., 1974
    - see also Anderson, Roland A.
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 1949-74
    - MacFetridge, Jean
    - see also Bender, George H.
    - see also Murray, Thomas E.
    - see also Ser. VIA, Development of nuclear power for peaceful purposes
    AEC; HDS chrono. of thermonuclear weapon program; Project Matterhorn/Sherwood; includes obit.
  - Strayer, J. R.
    - see Oates, Whitney J.
  - Streit, Clarence, 1954
  - Strickland, Donald A., 1962
  - Stripling, Robert E.
  - Strom, Ralph J., 1951
  - Strong, Harold F.
  - Strunsky, Robert, 1950-74
    - Miller, Arthur
  - Stryker, J. W.
  - Stumpf, John H.
  - Sturdevant, William L.
  - Sudbick, Joseph C.
  - Suga, Reinosuke, 1957
  - Suits, C. G., 1949
  - Sullivan, Charles A., n.d.
    bio.
  - Sullivan, Lucartha, 1944
  - Summerfield, Martin, 1957-65
    - see also Perkins, Courtland
  - Superintendent of Documents, 1957-64
  - Supplee, Henderson, Jr., 1945-64
  - Suratt, Samuel T., 1966-67
  - Survey Graphic, 1945-46
    - Kellogg, Paul
  - Sutton, Richard M.
  - Sutton, Roger Beatty, 1942
    - Schofield, Lemuel B.
  - Swann, W. F. G., 1958
  - Swanson, C. L. W., 1951
  - Swanson, Edgar
  - Swanson, Everett C., Sr., 1949
  - Swantek, Anthony, 1960
  - Swart, L. R.
  - Swartout, J. A., 1949-51
  - Sweeney, Mary, 1954-56
    - see also Nihlen, Marian M.
  - Swing, John Temple, 1986
  - Swinton, R. S.
  - Sykora, Artus
    - see Sandera, Karel
  - Sylvia, D. W., 1956
  - Syracuse University, 1950
    - Brown, Stuart Gerry
  - Szasz, Paul
  - Szilard, Leo, 1939-46
    - Blackett, [?]
    - Dirac, Paul
    - Joliot, G.
    - Kowarsky, [?]
    - von Halban, Hans
    copies of letters on early fission research; Smyth Report
  - Tackman, Arthur L., 1960 (Box Series I: 34)
  - Taémi, Selma, 1949
  - Tait, Malcolm R., 1965
    Atomic Indus. Forum
  - Tammaro, Al, 1949; 1958-60
  - Tape, Gerald F., 1955-69
    - see also Weisskopf, Victor F.
  - Taplin, Frank E., 1957
  - Taschek, R. F., 1964
  - Tater, [?], 1954
  - Taub, A[be] H., 1956; 1965
    von Neumann computer
  - Taylor, Charles F. (Mrs.), 1959
  - Taylor, David G., 1958
  - Taylor, Frank A.
  - Taylor, Hugh S., 1951-64
    - see also Arnold, J. H.
    - see also Ser. VIA, Princeton preceptorial on the air-[on atomic energy]
    re: Princeton
  - Taylor, R. V.
  - Taylor, Theodore B.
  - Taylor, William T., 1954
  - Teeter, John H.
  - Teller, Edward, 1950
    - Coiner, Richard T.
    - Tyler, [?]
    re: Critchfield
  - TenBroek, Carl
  - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1954-58
    - Adams, Sherman
    - Curtis, Harry A.
    - Davis, Joseph A.
    - Doub, George Cochran
    - Ellis, Clyde T.
    - Gamer, S. R.
    - Hughes, Rowland
    - Meeman, Edward J.
    - Penland, Clifford
    - Saltonstall, Leverett
    - Sturdevant, William L.
    - Taylor, R. V.
    - Vogel, Herbert D.
    Dixon-Yates contract
  - Tepe, J. B.
  - Termini, James A., 1953
  - Test, A. L.
    - see Brown, J. Douglas
    - see Wetterau, Elaine W.
  - Textile Research Institute, 1955
  - Thant, U.
    - see Zook, Donovan Q.
  - Thatcher, Sanford G., 1974
    HDS' corrections to bk. on JRO, Teller & H-bomb
  - Thayer, Harold E.
  - Thomas, Carl, n.d.
  - Thomas, Charles Allen, 1950
  - Thomas, Charles W., 1962-65
    - Balligand, P.
    - van Vuuren, P. H. J. J.
    - see also Ser. IV, Department of State misc.
  - Thomas, John B., 1963
    Univ. Res. Bd.
  - Thomas, Morgan, 1953-56
  - Thomas, Rupert B., 1945
  - Thomas, Trevor, 1958
  - Thomas, Wilmer J., 1956
  - Thompson, Alberto F., 1950
  - Thompson, Frank, Jr., 1970
  - Thompson, George P., 1947
  - Thompson, James S.
  - Thompson, Llewellyn E., 1965; 1972
    USSR & IAEA; obit.
  - Thompson, O. F.
  - Thompson, R. W., 1943
    metals shipment
  - Thompson, Richard S.
    - see Ser. IV, Disarmament
  - Thompson, Shelby, 1950-55
    - Brace, James H.
    - Holmes, Paul
  - Thompson, Theos J.
  - Thompson, W. I.
    - see Cohen, Karl
  - Thompson, Will S., 1945
  - Thomsen, D. L., Jr., 1957
  - Thomsen, LaVerne, 1965
  - Thomson, Lesslie R., 1945
  - Thorndike, Joseph J., Jr.
    - see Ser. VII, [Life magazine article]
  - Thornton, C. D. W.
  - Thorp, Willard, 1947
  - Thorton, R. L.
  - Thum, E. E., 1952; 1956
  - Thurnauer, Hans
  - Ticho, Harold K.
  - Timby, Elmer, 1954
  - Tingey, F. H.
  - Tisdale, W. E., 1924
  - Titanium Zirconium Co., Inc., 1951
    - Meredith, W. F.
    - Robinson, J. C.
  - Tober, Edward P.
  - Tobey, Lillian
  - Tobin, Irwin M., 1969
  - Tohamy, Hassan M., 1967
    re: Israeli nuclear lab.
  - Toll, David R.
  - Toll, John S., 1956
  - Tollestrup, Alvin V., 1967
  - Tolman, Richard C.
    - Baruch, Bernard M.
    - Brown, H. S.
    - Cooper, C. M.
    - Curtis, H. J.
    - Dempster, A. J.
    - Doan, R. L.
    - Nordheim, L. W.
    - Stone, R. S.
    - Wallace, [?]
    - Zirkle, R. E.
    - see also Cohen, Karl
    - see also Delsasso, Lewis A.
    - see Ser. V, Envelope 1b - Toleman, Richard C.
    re: Post War Policy Comm.; DSM Project
    - Folder #1, 1940 - Oct. 1944
    - Folder #2, Nov. 1944
    - Folder #3, Dec. 1944-46
      re: UNAEC
  - Tong, Marvin E.
  - Tonks, Lewi, 1955
  - Toussaint, Paul A., 1964-65; n.d.
  - Towne, Carroll A., 1952
    - Blucher, Walter H.
    re: Savannah River Project
  - Townsend, Jonathan
  - Townsend, Oliver
  - Tracy, W. Ward, 1947
  - Trail Creek Ranch, 1962
  - Trapnell, Edward R., 1954-62
    - Ball, George W.
    - Schlesinger, Arthur
    - see also Cleveland, Harlan
    AEC; IAEA; Atoms for Peace
  - Trayhern, [?], 1963
  - Traynor, Harry S., 1945; 1957; n.d.
    re: Manhattan Project
  - Trevithick, John P., 1952-76; n.d.
    IAEA; safeguards
  - Trexel, C. A., 1941
  - Trippe, J. T., 1962
  - Trowbridge, Augustus, 1921
  - Troxell, Thomas F., Jr.
  - Trudel, Allen R., 1956
  - Truman, Harry S., 1945-53
    - see also Dawson, Donald S.
    - see also Klauder, Louis T.
  - Trytten, M. H., 1957; 1961
    Hungarian refugees
  - Tubby, Roger W., 1967-69
  - Tucker, Albert W., 1958
  - Tucker, F. G., 1954
  - Tukey, John W., 1956; 1964
    Princeton, computers
  - Tumbleson, Robert
  - Turin, J. J.
    - see University of Toledo (Ohio)
  - Turkevich, John, 1962
  - Turnbull, Douglas C., Jr., 1957
    - see also Baltimore & Ohio Railroad Co.
  - Turner, A. E. (Pat), 1963-64
  - Turner, Edward L., 1960
  - Turner, Louis A., 1940-64
    - see also Coyle, Dan D.
    - see also Nielsen, Walter M.
    - see also Szilard, Leo
    - see also Ser. V, Envelope 1 - Alvarez, Luis
  - Turner, Louis A. (Mrs.), 1953
  - Tuttle, Charles R. M., 1951
    re: sci. testing
  - Tuttle, L. W., 1950
  - Tuve, Merle A.
    - Beckwith, Herbert L.
    - McPhee, John R.
    - Pflaum, D. J.
    OSRD, reports
    - Folder #1, 1940-43
    - Folder #2, 1944
      re: sweeping jammer proj.
    - Folder #3, 1945-51
      final report
  - Tyler, [?]
    - see Teller, Edward
  - Tyler, Carroll L., 1949-53
  - Tyroler, Charles, II, 1958
  - Uda, Koichi, 1957
  - Ufford, C. Wilbur, 1949; 1955-57
  - Ufford, Charles W., Jr., 1960
  - Uhlenbeck, G. E.
  - Ulrich, Max M.
  - Ulyat, William L., 1945
  - Underhill, Robert M.
    - see Froman, Darol
    - see Ser. II, Princeton University. OSRD...Sub-contract...
  - UNESCO, 1954
    - McCullough, Max
  - U.S. Department of Commerce, 1957
  - U.S. Department of State
  - U.S. Naval Medical School, 1950
    - Aston, M. J.
  - U.S. Weather Bureau, 1953
    - Reichelderfer, F. W.
  - Universities Research Association, Inc. (Box Series I: 35)
    - Bacon, Leonard L.
    - Bennett, Bradley F.
    - Bingham, Gordon McD.
    - Bowen, Howard R.
    - Brooks, Kennedy C.
    - Buchanan, Robert K.
    - Cagle, Fred R.
    - Davis, J. H.
    - Deutch, John M.
    - Eisenhower, Milton S.
    - Findlay, John W.
    - Friedlander, Gerhart
    - Giroux, Daniel S.
    - Goldwasser, Edwin L.
    - Greenewalt, C. H.
    - Gross, Mason W.
    - Hackerman, Norman
    - Hahn, T. Marshall, Jr.
    - Hamermesh, Morton
    - Harrington, Fred Harvey
    - Heffner, Hubert
    - Henricksen, G. C.
    - Henry, David D.
    - Heyns, Roger W.
    - Hicks, Maxine
    - Huson, F. R.
    - Kirk, Thomas
    - Lannutti, Joseph E.
    - Larsen, Carl W.
    - Lederman, Leon M.
    - Liddle, Urner
    - Limon, Peter
    - Livingston, M. Stanley
    - Lofgren, E. J.
    - Long, F. A.
    - Longenecker, Herbert E.
    - McKenzie, Lawson
    - MacRae, Donald A.
    - Madansky, Leon
    - Mann, Alfred
    - Manning, Thurston E.
    - Meid, G. Donald
    - Norman, A. G.
    - Packard, David
    - Pake, G. E.
    - Panofsky, W. K. H.
    - Peoples, John
    - Poillon, Donald K.
    - Polk, Irving
    - Pusey, Nathan M.
    - Reardon, Paul J.
    - Rees, Grahame
    - Robinson, G. de B.
    - Sachs, Robert G.
    - Sanford, J. R.
    - Schairer, George S.
    - Schlesinger, James R.
    - Segré, Emilio
    - Severiens, J. C.
    - Stahr, Elvis J.
    - Stever, H. Guyford
    - Thomas, Charles Allen
    - Ticho, Harold K.
    - Valk, Henry S.
    - Waldman, Bernard
    - Wall, Frederick T.
    - Wallenmeyer, William A.
    - Wallis, W. Allen
    - Warner, J. C.
    - Weinstein, Roy
    - Williams, Robert A.
    - Wilson, O. Meredith
    - Yamanouchi, Taiji
    minutes, reports, etc. re: 200 BeV accelerator
    - Folder #1, 1964-65
    - Folder #2, Jan.-May 1966
    - Folder #3, Jun.-Dec. 1966
    - Folder #4, 1967
    - Folder #5, 1968
    - Folder #6, Jan.-May 1969
    - Folder #7, Jun.-Dec. 1969 (Box Series I: 36)
    - Folder #8, 1970
    - Folder #9, 1971
    - Folder #10, 1972
    - Folder #11, 1973
    - Folder #12, 1974
    - Folder #13, 1975
    - Folder #14, 1976 (Box Series I: 37)
    - Folder #15, 1977-79; n.d.
  - University of California. Radiation Lab. Info. Division
  - University of Cambridge, 1923-24; n.d.
    - Brooke, Z. N.
    - Butler, Geoffrey
    - Pearce, E. C.
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1946
  - University of Toledo (Ohio), 1949
    - Turin, J. J.
    beryllium prod.
  - Unknown, 1945-72
    some HDS bio. material
  - Unna, Warren, 1956
  - Updike, Irving M.
  - Urey, Harold C., 1942-64
    - see also Kerr, Paul F.
    NDRC; Manhattan Proj. research; post-war research program on fission
  - Usmani, I. H., 1962-69
    IAEA & Pakistan
  - Valk, Henry S.
  - Vallely, Vincent P., 1963-64
  - Vanadium Corp. of America, 1950
    - Viles, D. W.
  - Van Atta, Chester M., 1960
  - Vance, Harold S., 1956
  - Vanden Bulck, C., 1944
    OSRD radial drill at Princeton
  - van der Meulen, P. A., 1956
    nuclear science program at Rutgers
  - Van der Poel, Priscilla, 1945
  - Vanderryn, Jack, 1968-70
    IAEA; small & medium power reactors
  - Van der Spek, J., 1962-64
  - Vander Weyden, A. J.
    - see Atomic Energy Comm. HDS consultant to
  - Van Doren, Carl
  - Van Doren, Charles N.
  - Van Dusen, Francis L., 1952
    - Scherbatskoy, Serge A.
    - Shipley, R. B.
    - Stowell, Averill
  - Van Dusen, Henry P. (Pitt), 1956; 1966
  - Van Dusen, L. H., 1918
    re: HDS WWI work at Aberdeen
  - Van Dyke, Mary, 1946
  - Van Haagen, Richard
  - Van Horn, E. L.
  - Van Houten, R. W., 1962
  - Van Vleck, John H., 1957
  - van Vuuren, P. H. J. J.
  - Veblen, Oswald
  - Vennard, Edwin
  - Verbrugge, Frank
  - Verdier, W. H., 1945
  - Vermeulen, Theodore, 1961
  - Vernon, H. C., 1944-45
  - Vernon, Jack
  - Ver Steeg, Clarence L., 1964
  - Vicker, Ray
    - see Wall Street Journal
  - Vickery, H. B., 1968
  - Victory, J. F., 1951
  - Viles, D. W.
    - see Vanadium Corp. of America
  - Vincent, Don
    - see Rollins College. Conference on World Government
  - Vincent, L. A., 1956
    - see also National Board of Fire Underwriters
  - Vincent, Robert H., 1945
    comments & corrections to Smyth Report; moral obligations of scientists
  - Vinciguerra, John V.
    - see Woodrow, Raymond J.
  - Visscher, Maurice B.
  - Vivian, L. L., 1955-70
  - Vivian, Rex, 1957
  - Vogel, Clark C., 1954
    re: JRO clearance case
  - Vogel, Herbert D.
  - Vogt, Roy S.
  - Volpe, Joseph, Jr., 1949; 1959
  - von Halban, Hans
  - von Hippel, Frank, 1975
  - von Karman, Theodor, 1956
  - von Keussler, Victor, 1924
  - von Kleinsmid, R. B.
  - Von Neumann, John, 1945-55
    - Water, J. W., Jr.
  - von Schirnding, K. R. S.
  - Waage, H. M., 1959 (Box Series I: 38)
  - Wachholz, Geo. J.
  - Wade, B. J.
  - Wade, Francis C., 1957
  - Wadsworth, J. J., 1951
  - Wahrenbrock, Howard E., 1958
  - Wainright, Stuyvesant
  - Wainwright, Alexander D.
  - Wakeling, Patricia R.
  - Wald, Robert
    - see American Inventory
  - Waldheim, Kurt, 1968-70
  - Waldman, Bernard, 1968
  - Walker, Eric A., 1954; 1955
  - Walker, John Curry
  - Walker, Sydnor H.
  - Wall, Frederick T.
  - Wall Street Journal, 1958
    - Vicker, Ray
    research at Princeton after Sputnik
  - Wallace, [?]
  - Wallace, C. K.
    - see Cook, Clinton S.
  - Wallace, John H., Jr., 1956
  - Wallenmeyer, William A.
  - Waller, Fletcher C., 1951-54
  - Walling, James E., 1961
  - Wallis, W. Allen
  - Wallner, [?]
    - see Farley, Philip J.
  - Walsh, Harry R., 1957
  - Walske, Carl
  - Walston, Oliver
    - see Macmillan Company
  - Walters, Everett, 1960-61
  - Walton, Henry W.
  - Ward, Archibald F., Jr., 1949
  - Wardwell, James F.
  - Ware, Thomas M., 1952
  - Ware lecture, 1955-56
    - Arnold, Melvin
    - Canaday, Ward M.
    - Eliot, Frederick May
    - McClellant, Nancy
    - McDougall, Kenneth
    - McGinness, Mason F.
    - Mendelsohn, Jack
  - Warfield, G.
  - Warheit, I. A., 1948
  - Waring, Frank A.
  - Warner, Beatrice
  - Warner, Frank
  - Warner, J. C., 1953-66
  - Warnock, Malcolm R.
  - Warren, Edward G., 1956
  - Warren, Frederick H., 1954
    - see also American Enterprise Association
  - Warren, Matthew M., 1957
  - Warren, Shields, 1952; 1967
    - Kelley, W. E.
    - see also Bonner, David
    - see also Shurcliff, William A.
    ionosphere research program
  - Washington Post, 1947
    - Elliston, Herbert
    re: Groves & release of Smyth Report
  - Water, J. W., Jr.
    - see Von Neumann, John
  - Waterfall, Wallace
    - see Barton, Henry A.
  - Waterman, Alan T., 1951-63
    - Buckley, Oliver
    - Middlebush, Frederick A.
    Nat. Science Found.; ultra-high energy accelerators
  - Waters, Frank, 1954
  - Waters, John A., 1950-57
    - Dunnington, F. G.
    - Shipley, Ruth B.
    - Van Dusen, Francis L.
    - see also Van Dusen, Francis L.
  - Watkins, G. E., 1958-59
  - Watkins, Ralph, 1954
  - Watson, Ernest C., 1941
  - Watson, Thomas J., 1945
  - Watson, William W., 1947-62
  - Watts, Elizabeth B., 1962-63
  - Waymack, W. W., 1949
  - Weaver, Charles H., 1961
  - Weaver, Warren, 1959
  - Webb, Harold W.
  - Webb, James E.
  - Webb, T. J., 1953
    -Lillie, David W.
    osmium
  - Webber, R. T.
  - Weber, Kay, 1957
  - Webster, D. S.
  - Webster, William, 1949-64
  - Weeks, Dorothy W., 1945-53
  - Weeks, Edward, 1954
    - see also Ser. VIII, Stopping the atomic...
  - Wehmeyer, David
  - Wei, Chan Wah, 1951
  - Weidenmann, Hans, 1949
  - Weigle, Richard D., 1958
    - see also Cleveland, Richard F.
  - Weil, George L., 1950-51
  - Weinberg, Alvin M., 1949-68
    - Dunlap, G. W.
    - Katz, Donald L.
    - Leverett, M. C.
    - Roboff, S. B.
    AEC; Oak Ridge Lab; small reactors; Nuclear Energy Soc.
  - Weiner, Charles
  - Weinstein, Roy, 1966
  - Weiss, David H., 1965-66
  - Weiss, Nancy J., 1986
  - Weisskopf, Victor F., 1952-65
    - Blatt, John
    re: VFW book on nuclear physics
  - Weller, Lawrence, 1945
  - Wells, Algie A., 1959-68
    - Hefner, Frank K.
    - Tohamy, Hassan M.
    - see also O'Donnell, Ashton J.
    - see also Webster, William
    AEC; IAEA
  - Wells, Walter, 1954
  - Welsh, Richard S.
  - Wensel, H. T.
    - Aebersold, Paul C.
    - Marden, John W.
    - Thompson, R. W.
    - Folder #1, 1941-42
      Manhattan Proj.; German scientists in S-1 field
    - Folder #2, 1943
      OSRD lists of reports, drawings
    - Folder #3, 1944
      electromagnetic separation at Berkeley; isotron w/drawings
  - Wensley, William R[ichard]
    - see Harshaw Chemical Company
  - Went, J. J., 1954
    - Hall, [?]
  - Wenzel, W[illiam] A.
  - Werner, Louis, 1959
  - Wessman, Harold E., 1950
  - West, Andrew F., 1921; 1923
    - Rutherford, E[rnest B.]
    - see also Ser. II, Princeton University. Appointments
    re: HDS research at Princeton & Cambridge
  - Western Electric Company, 1917
    - Jewett, F. B.
    - Jones, R. L.
    HDS Summer job
  - Western Periodicals Co.
  - Westinghouse Electric & Manufacturing Company, 1942-56
    - Rentschler, H. C.
    supplies to Princeton; purity of uranium
  - Wetterau, Elaine W., 1956
  - Wever, E. G., 1956
  - Weyl, Joachim F., 1960
  - Wheat, Henry A., Jr., 1949
  - Wheeler, John Archibald
    - Ives, H. E.
    - May, Andrew J.
    - Schein, Marcel
    - Smith, Datus C., Jr.
    - Snyder, John W.
    - Teller, Edward
    - York, Herbert
    - see also Kluych, Alex R.
    - see also Mulliken, Robert S.
    - Folder #1, 1940-45
      setting up uranium research at Palmer Lab; post-war reactors
    - Folder #2, 1947-77; n.d.
      increased LASL work on thermonuclear reactions, 1951
  - Wheeler, Richard S., 1957
  - Wherry, Kenneth S., 1951
  - Whetten, N. L., 1964
  - Whitaker, M. D.
    - see Ser. V, Envelope 1 - Whitaker, M. D.
  - White, A. E., 1941
  - White, Donald R., 1960
  - White, [Freddie], 1959
  - White, George, 1959
  - White, Katharine E., 1958
  - White, Milton G., 1941-73
    - Leenhouts, Hugh D.
    MIT; Princeton accelerator
  - White, Stanley
    - see Ser. VIA, [Two hundred BeV accelerator]
  - White, Theodore H.
    - see Reporter. The
  - Whitman, Walter G., 1955; 1957
    - see also Hesburgh, Theodore M.
    - see also Ser. VIA, Science and peace
  - Whitmer, Charles A., 1950
  - Whiton, Herman F., 1953
  - Whitton, John, 1956; 1962
  - Whitwell, J. C., 1957; 1959
  - Wickett, Walton A., 1950 (Box Series I: 39)
  - Widdoes, Lawrence C.
  - Widenmann, Hans A., 1953-75
  - Wieck, Fred D., 1956; 1957
  - Wiesner, F. C., 1959
    - Fenn, John Bennett
    - Gates, Thomas S., Jr.
  - Wiesner, Jerome B.
  - Wiggin, Edwin A., 1984; 1986
  - Wightman, A. S.
  - Wigner, Eugene P.
    - Creutz, Edward C.
    - Mahoney, John H.
    - see also Ser. V, Envelope 1 - Wigner, Eugene P.
    - Folder #1, 1942-43
      Manhattan Proj. personnel
    - Folder #2, 1944-47
      Princeton experiments; use of 23
    - Folder #3, 1949-53
      biological warfare; JRO & classified material
    - Folder #4, 1954-77; n.d.
      Russian A-bomb
  - Wilbur, G. A., 1946
  - Wilder, Mary
  - Wiley & Sons, Inc. John, 1947; 1957
    - Palmer, Douglas S.
  - Wilhelm, R. H., 1956-60
  - Wilkes, Daniel M., 1969
  - Wilkins, Ernest H.
  - Wilks, S. S.
  - Williams, Charles W., 1959
  - Williams, Clarke, 1957
  - Williams, Dorothy E.
  - Williams, Dudley, 1959
  - Williams, Frederic H., 1948
  - Williams, Harrison A., Jr., 1962
  - Williams, John C., 1957-58
  - Williams, John H., 1960
  - Williams, Robert A.
  - Williams, Robert Chadwell, 1983-84
  - Williams, Robert W.
  - Williams, Van Zandt, 1945-46
  - Williams, Walter J., 1950-52; n.d.
    - Hinshaw, Carl
    - see also Glazer, Guilford
    - see also University of Toledo (Ohio)
  - Willis, C. H.
    - see Shobert, Eric I., II
  - Willrich, Mason, 1966-69; n.d.
  - Wills, William A., 1948
  - Wilson, Carroll L., 1941-54
    - see also Volpe, Joseph, Jr.
  - Wilson, Charles E.
  - Wilson, E. Bright, Jr., 1949-51
  - Wilson, Eugene H., 1948
  - Wilson, Joseph C., 1962
  - Wilson, O. Meredith, n.d.
  - Wilson, Richard, 1968
  - Wilson, Robert
  - Wilson, Robert E., 1960-68
    - Henderson, C. L.
  - Wilson, Robert R., 1941-68
    - Hall, Thomas S.
    - see also McMillan, Priscilla Johnson
    isotron proj.
  - Wilson, T. B.
    - see Maher, William K.
  - Wilson, Volney C., 1956
  - Wilson, Willard, 1957
  - Wilson, Woodrow
  - Winckler, John R., 1949
  - Wingfield, W. O., 1947
  - Winne, Harry A.
  - Winslow, Richard K.
    - see Doubleday & Company, Inc.
    - see New York Herald Tribune
  - Winterich, John T.
    - see Saturday Review of Literature
  - Winters, Robert A., 1950-56
  - Wise, Robert E., 1949
  - Wishengrad, H., 1945
  - Withington, F. S., 1954
  - Witsell, Edward F.
    - see Mercer, George L.
  - Wolfe, Hugh C., 1955
  - Wolfers, Arnold
  - Wolfle, Dael, 1963
  - Wolverton, Charles A.
  - Wonsetler, J. B., 1947
  - Wood, Richard H., 1956
  - Woodhull, [?], 1959
  - Woodrow, Raymond J., 1948-68
    - Vinciguerra, John V.
    - see also Carothers, S.
    - see also Hess, H[arry] H.
    - see also Princeton University. Scientific Research & Higgins Fund Comm.
    patents, accelerator at Princeton; AEC; Matterhorn
  - Woodruff, Nathan, 1952; 1955
  - Woods, Lawrence C.
  - Woodward, J. Taylor, 1955
  - Woolley, Samuel H.
  - Wormser, Felix E.
  - Worsey, A. S., 1949
  - Worth, Daniel F., 1952
  - Worthington, Hood, 1954
  - Wright, Chilton A., 1954
  - Wright, Sydney L., 1945-50
  - Wright, T. P.
  - Wright, William E., 1954
  - Wrigley, Hank J.
  - Wriston, Henry M., 1957
  - Wu, Nelson I., 1969
  - Yamanouchi, Taiji
  - Yasukawa, Daigoro, 1957
  - Yates, Carlyle E., 1956
  - Yeomans, Ed, 1946
  - Yeomans, William L., 1961-65; n.d.
    - Gardner, Richard N.
    - Goswami, Upendra L.
    - see also Met, Viktor
    - see also Sporn, Philip
    Advis. Comm. on U.S. Policy in IAEA
  - Yoe, John H., 1954-55
  - Yokoyama, Sumi, 1951
  - York, Herbert
  - Yost, Charles F., 1964
  - Young, Arthur M., 1960
  - Young, Donald
  - Young, Herbert A., 1945
    Smyth Report-chemists at Y-12
  - Young, Hoylande D., 1953-54
  - Young, Raymond J., 1955-56
  - Young, Wilbur M., 1956-64
  - Yust, Walter, 1956
    - see also Encyclopedia Britannica
  - Zabusky, N. J., 1965
  - Zacharias, Jerrold R., 1949-52
  - Zaki, Aftab H., 1959
  - Zeeman, Christopher, 1955
  - Zeitlin, Stanley
  - Zeldin, Richard P., 1957
    - see also McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc.
  - Zeleny, John, 1924-25
  - Zeletsoff, Michael, 1947
  - Ziegler, Benjamin M., 1950
  - Zilsel, P. R.
  - Zinn, W. H., 1949-61
    - see also Barschall, Heinz H.
  - Zirkle, R. E.
  - Zook, Donovan Q., 1966-79; n.d.
    - Thant, U.
    - see also Jacques, Philippe G.
    - see also Sole, D. B.
    - see also Trevithick, John P.
    - see also Vanderryn, Jack
    - see also Ser. VIB, Conway, John T.
  - Zukert, Eugene M., 1953-61
    - Barlow, Robert
    - Campbell, Joseph
    - Kelehan, James L.
    - Snapp, [?]
  - Zulker, C.